Matt Spaulding

Software Engineering Leader

(727) 324-8369 mrmattspaulding@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a curious technologist with a Masters degree in Computer Science and over thirteen years of professional software engineering experience. I have a passion for leading people and helping others grow and succeed. Over the last six years, I have led software engineering teams that have built world-class products using cutting-edge technologies. My focus is on coaching, mentoring, and thought leadership, driving best practices in software development and establishing the north star in technology vision.

EXPERIENCE

Weaver, Tampa FL (Remote) — Chief Technology Officer

APR 2023 - PRESENT

- Launched a new dating app for iOS and Android.
- Used React Native to develop a compelling user interface.
- Built API with Nodejs.
- Stored user data with PostgreSQL database.
- Hosted application servers with AWS elastic cloud service.
- Verified user identities with Twilio API.
- Developed a complex algorithm which matched users based on many, many parameters using a weighted system.
- link

Spekit, Denver CO (Remote) — *Software Engineering Manager*

JAN 2022 - JULY 2022

- Lead the development of a B2B SaaS product funded by Craft Ventures.
- Empathetically led a brilliant team of engineers in a cross-functional multi-squad environment.
- Aligned squads with high-impact business goals and lead agile engineering practices while working closely with product and design.
- Coached engineers in their professional development to uncover growth opportunities and create a culture of continuous improvement.
- Regularly held 1:1 meetings with engineers and other leaders to uncover opportunities for growth.
- Interviewed and onboarded new engineers so they felt welcome and were able to hit the ground running.
- Peer reviewed engineer's technical contributions in a React/Python/PostgreSQL stack with Github pull requests.

SOCIAL PROFILES

MattSpaulding.org

Stack Overflow

Github

LeetCode

SKILLS

Gemeni AI

OpenAI

Reactjs

Next.js

React Native

Typescript

Javascript

Node

HTML

SCSS

Tailwind

PostgreSQL

Mongo

AWS

Vercel

Github

NATIONALITY

US Citizen

PwC, Tampa FL (Remote) — Software Engineering Manager

MAR 2020 - NOV 2021

- Developed an enterprise cloud-based web application for a global accounting firm.
- Collaborated with business leaders to understand the business model, opportunities, and challenges.
- Provided technical direction and mentorship for engineers.
- Upheld a high standard code and design principles by leading code reviewing sessions.
- Utilized Azure DevOps ecosystem, creating work items, reviewing pull requests, and deployment pipelines.

LoanLogics, Jacksonville FL (Remote) — *Software Engineering Manager*

OCT 2018 - DEC 2019

- Developed v1.0 of enterprise cloud-based web application for leading mortgage loan underwriting company.
- Worked with stakeholders to determine scope of project and staffing needs to complete the project by the deadline.
- Hired and mentored a team of 15 developers.
- Developed Angular v8 applications using the latest design patterns, such as NgRx, and connected to a Java Web API.
- Implemented microservices architecture for better scaling of independent development teams and fault isolation in production.
- Deployed in AWS DevOps ecosystem using Jenkins to deliver docker containers to a cluster of Amazon EC2 instances.
- Tested code with Jasmine, Karma, and Cypress.

iProcedures, Tampa FL (Remote) — Tech Lead Software Engineer

MAR 2016 - OCT 2018

- Developed a cloud-based mobile Anesthesia Information Management System (AIMS).
- Developed a real-time vitals monitor using the D3.js charting library.
- Created Windows and Mac desktop applications using Electron.
- Automated versioning and deployment system to deliver updates to clients using Azure DevOps Services.
- Peer reviewed junior developers using the Gitflow workflow.

Toptal, San Francisco CA (Remote) — Software Engineer

SEPT 2015 - MAR 2016

The Learning Experience

- Created Bubble's U, a children's learning platform, for a nation-wide academy of early education.
- Developed in Angular v6 with custom UI components.
- link

Herndonwood Associates

- Created ReKoN, a risk management platform, for a banking institution.
- Developed in C#.Net using MVC pattern and JQuery Bootstrap frontend.
- Implemented Azure as the cloud server and storage solution.
- Created a multi-level role system.

Wolters Kluwer Law & Business, Tampa FL (Remote) — Software Engineer

JAN 2014 - SEPT 2015

- Developed MediRegs, a medical coding suite, for a global provider of technology solutions.
- Built a tool that uses fuzzy logic to find ICD10 codes.
- Built with C#.Net and Angular.js in the Azure cloud.

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — Software Engineer

NOV 2012 - OCT 2013

- Built the Office Depot Windows Store app.
- Worked with the Office Depot development team to create a custom API.

AgileThought, Tampa FL — Software Engineer

AUG 2012 - NOV 2012

• Built custom software using C#.Net with knockout.js frontend.

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — Software Engineer

DEC 2011 - AUG 2012

- Converted several eCommerce websites into mCommerce mobile websites.
- Scraped HTML from the websites and presented the data as JSON through a RESTful C#.Net Web API.

Enporion, Tampa FL — Junior Software Engineer

IAN 2011 - DEC 2011

- Developed an online reverse auction website for municipality utilities.
- Built with C#.Net MVC and Adobe Flex.

Raytheon, Largo FL — Junior Software Engineer

MAY 2009 - JULY 2010

- Developed software for a major U.S. Defense company.
- Developed a tool to automate calibration of electrical equipment in Basic. (Voltameter, oscilloscope, etc.)

EDUCATION

University of South Florida, Tampa FL Master of Science in Computer Engineering

2011

GPA: 3.25

Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society President

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Questanda

- Developed a generative AI that answers all of your questions.
- Uses Google Gemini AI.
- Built with Next.js.
- Authentication with NextAuth and Redis database.
- <u>link</u>

Givvn

- Developed a tool for nonprofit organizations to build communities and collect donations.
- SaaS platform allows nonprofits to build websites and donation forms.
- Cloud CRM manages supporters and automatically sends emails to promote engagement.
- Built on the MERN stack (Mongo, Express, React, Node) with Next.js and served by Vercel.
- link

Moonport

- Developed a video game.
- Set in the year 1985, an astronaut aspires to conquer the moons of Saturn.
- Built with Godot game engine using GDScript.
- link